Guide to the Palo Alto Stock Farm Photographs
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Palo Alto Stock Farm photographs
1880-1885
PC0077
Hill, Andrew Putnam, 1853-1922.
0.25 Linear feet
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Information about Access
Open for research.
Biographical/Historical note
Charles Conklin Wooster, born in Albany, NY, in 1845, was a horse trainer and coachman for Leland Stanford from about 1870 until Stanford's death in 1893. He continued to work for Jane Stanford, and after her death in 1905, for the University. He died in 1935
Scope and Contents
Images in this collection include Stock Farm horses Electioneer and Lady Russel; Leland Stanford, Jr., with the horse Cheatano, 1882; trainers and grooms at the Stock Farm, 1881 and 1884; two trotters racing; and the Wooster home on campus. Other images include a logging wagon and a portrait of Fire Chief Dolen (city not given). Many of the Stock Farm photographs were taken by A. P. Hill. The collection also includes obituaries on Wooster, 1935.
Access Terms
Meredith, Leah; Meredith, Roy; Wooster, Charles Conklin; Horses --Pictorial works.; Palo Alto (Calif.) Stock Farm
Collection Contents
- Photographs (Box 1)
  - Clippings on C.C. Wooster, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Carriage Horses by Barn (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Charles Marvin Men at Stock Farm, 1881 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Electioneer, 1884 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Electioneer, 1885 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Electioneer Pres. Mrs. Harrison (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - First work crew at Stanford (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Lady Russel horse, 1884 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Leland Stanford Jr horse, 1882 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Stock Farm paddocks, 1880 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Stock Farm Paddocks, 1880 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Trainers, 1884 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - trainers and grooms, 1884 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Two trotters on track (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Wooster home on Stanford campus (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Fire Chief Oolen (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Logging wagon (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - 2 men in carriage (Box 1, Folder 16)